This is CodeTap
I'm Marian
and I'm Carol
and today we'll be talking about
What is HTML?
So, what is HTML?
Well, most tutors will tell you
that HTML stands for:
Hyper Text
Markup Language
Isn't that adding up to the confusion?
Well, to tell you the truth,
I'd be even more confused too.
Let me translate
Geek into English
Let's switch to the big screen then.
OK. So, let's see what HTML does.
What's up with it?
What does it do?
When you write HTML, you actually
define the structure of a web page.
Let's dive in and see an example
of a very popular web site.
YouTube
I'll open Google Chrome browser
and Notepad
and set them side by side
and let's navigate to YouTube
OK, so we'll start writing down
the structure of YouTube
A very simple one to illustrate the purpose.
So, we can see that
we have a top section here.
So let's write "top-section"
and in that top section
we have a logo
and the logo contains
info about YouTube GB
OK, and after the logo, to its right side
we have a search
and after that we have a ...
let's call it "mini-menu"
'cause of some small icons
those ones, those three over here
So, in this mini-menu we have a
an upload icon
I think those are called alerts
so "alerts"
and the last one would be
the user profile
so far so good,
we could continue with
let's call it "menu list"
OK, and this one has a link
that gets you home
and another link
for trending
and another link for subscriptions
so, I think we can continue with this
we can call it the "content" section, OK?
so, because it has content in it
and we see recommended
and it's a list of movies
so "re..." list
and inside it we have "movie 1"
movie two, movie three, and so on.
and we have a "watch it again" list, "lifestyle"
so let me just copy / paste this
and say watch it again list
and we have again movies and so on and
later on we have more lists
later on we'll get to the bottom of it
we have a footer
so let's just jump to it, "footer"
and some footer
lots of nice content with lots of useful info
OK, so now we know that with HTML
you define the structure of a web page
in the next lesson, I'll reveal to you
The rules of writing HTML
the very very simple rules
of writing HTML
so, see YOU in the next lesson!