Cum să eviți să fii respins la interiviu?
Două sfaturi criminale pentru dezvoltatori web sau programatori.
Te duci des la interviuri și te simți depăsit?
Ți se pun întrebări greu de răspuns sau pentru care nu le știi răspunsul?
Le arăți că știi ceva în timp ce ei se așteaptă la altceva?
Hai să aflăm cum poți lua controlul interviului înapoi.
Înainte de "Sfatul #1" spune-mi de unde ești într-un comentariu mai jos?
și cât este ora acum?
Sfatul #1
Ar trebui să începi prin a le aduce aminte că natura interviului este
de a vă cunoaște mai bine.
iar acest proces este limitat de timpul alocat interviului.
Ar trebui să închizi afirmația cu:
Cred că toți suntem de acord cu asta
altfel nu ar mai exista interviuri secundare.
Acest lucru va înmuia atmosfera și îi va deschide pentru urmatoarea întrebare
Urmează prin a le cere să faci o concept dovadă.
un proiect mic prin care să le dovedești de ce ești în stare înainte să ia o decizie.
Așa ca întreabă ce ar dori să te vadă lucrând pentru ei?
Dacă au vreo preferință pentru o anumită tehnologie ...
sau dacă ești liber să le arăți tot ce ai mai bun.
This will definitely raise their interest and unless there are some unknown factors
you should get a chance for a second interview with them
You can approach the solution to this project as you wish
as well as to tailor a story about why you took a certain approach over another
and how would that benefit them either in short run or in the long run
Now SMASH that Like button for TIP #1 cause I know you like what you hear
Tip #2
Following the "learn to code like a pro", "build your online resume" and
"build a quick blog" playlists of CodeTap
you'll discover how to create client optimised websites
that can achieve a perfect
Google Page Speed Score
That means that your projects, your websites are 100% search engine optimised
are very very SEO friendly.
with this asset in your hand, prepare ahead of the interview
go grab the link of the page of the interviewer as well as
3 to 5 links of their top competitors
or if it's a Digital Agency, 3 to 5 links of their clients
and get back to them with something like:
how would you like me to help you out
to optimise you web page and stand out in front of your competitors
How would you like me to help you out so you'd be able to go to your clients
and propose to them to get a perfect Google Page Speed Score
on their website and crush their competitors on this level.
with this said, the interview is not even over, it's in progress
and you're already providing them with possible future value.
they can see in you potential
Now smash that LIKE button for "Tip #2"
Those two tips helped me as well as some of my students and friends and colleagues
to get their dream job or at least have a higher chance in the interview process
If you're new over here this is CodeTap
where you'll master how to create websites and get paid well
so smash that Subscribe Button Now and smash that like button as well.
Thank you, thank you, thank you, thank you for so much smashing, I like your smashing
And as always: Happy Coding and Create something awesome!