5 tips
on how to become a web developer coming up
Tip #1
Volunteering or interning.
This is the quickest way to get hired
or freelance as a web developer.
So your question might be:
Hey, is there someone in the local area that needs their website done?
Tip #2
Say yes to every website, including unpaid ones.
Tip #3
Build your portfolio.
Tip #4
Find a mentor
90% of the time spent as a beginner is looking at errors and doing things the wrong way.
Finding a mentor is a game changer.
A mentor will guide you on the right path if you go too far sideways.
If you’re new over here this is CodeTap
where you’ll discover how to build websites and
get paid well.
To watch the full episode of this video
visit the link in the bottom part of this video,
type it in the address bar of your browser and hit enter.