5 tips
on how to become a web developer coming up
Tip #1
Volunteering or interning.
This is the quickest way to get hired
or freelance as a web developer.
The very first time that I started doing web stuff was for a clan of gamers I was part of.
It started as a passion, as I wanted us to be online somehow,
and stand out in front of other gaming clans.
Soon after, I’ve done the website for the internet cafe
where I was volunteering to help out with network administration and clients.
In exchange I got access to internet and computers
since at that time I didn’t own one nor had the money to buy it.
Some of you might relate to this.
So your question might be:
Hey, is there someone in the local area that needs their website done?
Or … Can I join as an intern and learn from the more experienced web developers?
Tip #2
Say yes to every website, including unpaid ones.
This doesn’t mean that you should always work for free.
Your goal is to gain experience in the real world as quickly as possible and build your portfolio.
With the free ones you can say something like this:
Let’s help each other out. I’ll build this website for you for free
and in return, at the end, if you’re happy with my work
feel free to help me out and pay whatever you think it worths or what you can afford.
I’ve done lots of websites for friends and family for free which gave me a lot of confidence.
So start saying yes now by smashing that like button!
Tip #3
Build your portfolio.
I’ll start by assuring you that this step is totally optional.
I know lots of coders including myself that started without a portfolio.
However, if you are not confident and don’t have the guts to speak for yourself
and sell a good value to your possible employer or client,
the portfolio, your work, will speak for you.
So where do you put your work?
Well, this can be your own web site and I recommend this if you want to look professional.
Those days you can get pretty good cheap deals to buy a domain name.
I use gandi.net.
You can also host it on GitHub.com and GitHub.io all for FREE.
Check the playlist “Learn to code like PRO”
and “Build your online resume” which you can find
in the links above or in the description below.
Tip #4
Find a mentor and join local or online coding groups.
You can find lots of those ones on FaceBook, LinkedIn
or google for the ones that suits you most.
You want to identify and follow the best ones in web development
and gain as much experience as you can from them
so one day you’d become better and inspire others just like yourself at this time.
90% of the time spent as a beginner is looking at errors and doing things the wrong way.
Finding a mentor is a game changer.
A mentor will guide you on the right path if you go too far sideways.
I’ll be happy to be your online mentor and I aim to answer all questions I’m able to.
Uuuuu, online mentor? Sounds cool? Hell ya so smash that like button.
Tip #5
Get the word out.
Building websites, paid or free, come on ....
Building websites, building websites, paid or free
How? Well there is this thing called “Social Media” like: YouTube, StackOverflow, GitHub,
all the forums you can think of in your niche and so many more.
Attend local networking events like: Free Code Camp, Google Campus and so many more.
I’ve found lots o them on meetup.com so go on and check it out.
This is how you’ll make new connections and how people will discover you.
You’ll build your online presence, brick by brick with:
Each meeting you attend and interact with people
Each question you answer on a forum, group or special website like StackOverflow
Each “pull request” to a public open source project on GitHub
A few brick layers or even an entire wall with
each cool public project you work on available on GitHub
If you’re new over here this is CodeTap
where you’ll discover how to build websites and
get paid well.
So smash that like button and subscribe now if you haven’t done so.
Thanks for watching and as always:
happy coding and create something awesome!
Come one, building ....