So attributes in PUG, so many ways to play with them. We are almost done with this so let's continue.
In here I'll create a new file: id.pug
Close the other one and I'll drag the id.html over here
And close this one. So basically to create an "id' is similar to the CSS selector, you just do
An "a" tag with the # or whatever you call this sign over here
And my-id. I save it, you can see that the tag is generated here, yeeey
Ok, now if we want to create a div
We can say div#my-other-id
And we can also continue with a class: .my-class
However, as you remember, div is the default one
So we can just omit it like that
And this would be #my-other-other-id
Because ids should be unique, nothing stops you from actually typing
Identical ids, but ids are unique
Which are not identical, so pay attention to that
Classes can be repeated easily in HTML
Ok, so now we've got #my-id, #my-other-id and #my-other-other-id cause I'm running out of ideas
So now let's play with the ampersand &attributes
special-attributes.pug
I'll drag this one over ... no, I'll drag this one over here
Than look for special-attributes.html, drag it over here, close that and close that
Ok so over here let's make an object
var myObject = {} and let's do
Html, not html, let's do:
src: and the value would be 'path.jpg'
Whatever, and then width: '100'
Would be enough, and now
Let's create an "img" tag
With the class as .nice-image
And then let's pass the &attributes
And this would be like a function call
And we pass "myObject" into it, see what happens
yeeey, so we've got these attributes and and it
created it over here. Now let's pass another one
class: 'big', so if we do this
We can see that it kind of joined this class over here
With this one over here. So this is the &attributes inside Pug
So did you have fun looking at attributes inside PUG language that generates HTML?
Well next time we'll start talking about case
So, happy hacking!