Welcome back to "Meet Pug"
We've done so many so lessons so far, however I want you to have access
To the code that I'm writing. So for that I'm not going to do
Pug right now, we're just going to quickly make this project available online. So follow me.
So over here I'll open the console and
Actually I'll open a new one over here, a new terminal and if I say:
git remote -v
It shows that it's still pointing to marianzburlea/pug-starter, so
Let's assume you want this to be your project, so
I'll quickly open a new window over here
And I will go on GitHub
And github.com/codatepio
So let's assume that "codetapio" will be your username, not mine, which is marianzburlea
Over here I'll create a new project
meet-pug
Create repository. Now I want to point to: codetapio/meet-pug
Not to marianzburlea/pug-starter so all I have to do is:
Remove the connection to git
Anyway. I also want to remove history so I'll just say:
rm -rf which is remove recursive with force
This is remove, this is recursive and this is with force
And I'll remove the ".git" folder
git status
Now git no longer knows anything about it
"git init" will reinitialise git
"git add ." everything and
git commit -m "meet pug is quite awesome"
And now all I have to do is to copy those two lines
or those two lines. They are one and the same.
Paste them over here, press "Enter", give it a second
And now if I refresh the page
You can see that we got
All of our files that we've written so far accessible and
On the web, on GitHub, open sourced
And I'll continue to make commits and you can find all those files on:
https://github.com/codetapio/meet-pug
So see you in the next lesson!