So let's play some more with attributes in PUG
Last time we've played with quoted attributes and attributes interpolation
Actually over here, let's quickly change this one, like that. And we can also do:
+ '.html' so this is like JavaScript
OK, let's save it. We can see that it's the same thing.
Especially if you do like: ?a=2
We can see that the change gets propagate here
That was another thing about attribute interpolation.
So now let's close some of those files and create a new file
unescaped.pug
That's unescaped.pug and unescaped.html, split
And let's leave it like that for a second.
OK, so let's do another div
And inside it let's make:
code="name"
And, actually, let's make it horizontal, it's easier for you to see.
We can see that this one gets converted into this one, however this is lesser than sign
This is the lesser than sign
And then it's "b" and it's the greater than sign, undo ...
So it's not exactly what we wanted. So if we want to "unescape" it.
Let's put some pipes, right? We want to "unescape" it,
We want to put an exclamation "!" before that equal "="
This is escaped, this is unescaped
Now let's see some other things
Let's play with the boolean ones
boolean.pug
Ok, let's move boolean.pug here, and boolean.html here
Now let's do an "input" tag and inside here we'll type: type="text"
And then we'll do "checked"
Save it, we can see that this is the output of that
Let's do a couple of pipes and then: input(type="radio")
And we can say: checked=true
So, again, checked, checked
And then let's duplicate this one and do checked=false
So, in this case checked is omitted
However if we are to specify: doctype html
html
It knows not to mirror the checked attribute
Which means it just gonna output this one
If we want to actually output the "checked" one,
Let's duplicate this and do: true
If we save it we can see, checked here
And we can say: if true, if this is true
Which it is right now
We can type 'checked'
And now we've got checked="checked"
And this is the unescaped and the boolean attributes in PUG
Happy Hacking!