More attributes in PUG
So last time we've talked about attributes and multiline attributes. Now let's talk about
quoted attributes and attributes interpolation
Let's see if we can close everything here
and let's make a new file:
quoted-attributes.pug
And that means that we also have "quoted-attributes.html". Let's drag it over here.
And quoted attributes, so let's see, let's see.
Maybe we have a div and if anybody has played with Angular so far
In angular we can have, let's see ... whatever
class="nice"
And then we can have a (click) event
And this would be calling "myFunction()"
And let me also quickly open the command line, over here, and if we save it
We can see that we get an error. In order to get rid of that error
We can do a comma over there. If we save it we can see that over here
No more errors, everything looks fine and dandy, or ...
We can omit that comma. Actually let's duplicate this line
Do two pipes and then omit this comma
if we save it, we get back that error. However if we select this
And do single quotes around it we can see that
We get the same output. So this is quoted attributes.
Now let's do one more: attribute interpolation
attribute-interpolation.pug
Let's drag it over here. So this attribute interpolation
Which means, ... let's open a JavaScript and say:
- var myUrl = 'http://codetap.io/cv'
This is where you can download your free template resume
It's actually my personal one. This is the one that I use when I go to interviews
So, with that said let's do now an "a" tag with a "href"
href=myUrl
So if we save it, we can see that it generated this, so I'll
Add a label: click to download your free CV template
Now we've generated this HTML over here.
Let's just make less text. Cool
So now we say again:
- var myUrl ... I'm not sure if it'll conflict, let's just try it, and this will be: contact.html
Then another "a" tag with href=myUrl and "Contact me"
Let's see now. We've got two of them side by side and I think we need
Here a pipe, or two. Let's see if we put two pipes like that. Does it work?
Or .. no, it just makes another pipe.
This was attribute interpolation and quoted attributes in PUG
Let's see each other in the next lesson!