So how do you save time writing html
how do you become more efficient,
how do you deliver a project
that maybe takes 5 days in just 2 days,
well let's talk about that
Well, to improve your efficiency in writing HTML
usually you have to use a template engine
and if you quickly Google
we can find that there is a big list
and among them there are like:
pug, ejs, handlebars, nunjucks, and so many others.
So I'll give her a handful of reasons or more
on why you should use a template engine
and make sure to stay till the end
as there'll be a bonus!
So let's start with: number one
Separation. You can have the data or the model in one side
and then the view or the presentation on another side.
Number two is: structure
You can structure your code into components
which will hold a basic functionality
with everything that is related to it:
HTML, CSS, images, JavaScript, tests
and so many more.
Number three is readable.
If you look at this code
especially the PUG template engine for HTML
it's TAB based just like "Python"
and it's easy to read.
As soon as you look at it
you'll understand its structure,
who's the parent, who's the child
and what attributes are used inside.
Number four: collaboration
If the code has a good structure,
colaboration will come quite easily.
So if your project scales up
and new joiners will come
it'll be very easy for them
to just look at the code,
pick it up and start developing.
Number five: most template engines
are quite easy to learn.
You should spend no more
than a couple of hours
and sometimes up to a day
but that would be all and
you'll quickly learn
a template engine that will:
SAVE TIME
And this is my favorite feature
cause I always prefer
to spend the extra time
with my family, friends
or actually doing some research
or other cool projects
than repeating myself
or doing something inefficiently.
So with a template engine that's
well structured, easy to read
people can collaborate and so on
you can definitely save time which will make
most of the time your clients happy
and of course you can put time to better use
So guys I gave you a hand full of reasons or more
on why you should use a template engine
for writing HTML
So we've got to the bonus and
I'm quite excited to let you know
that this video marks the beginning of a series
of a step by step, from scratch tutorials,
in depth about how to use a template engine
we'll be diving into PUG, former Jade,
and we'll be doing some real world examples
on how to use that, so stay tuned.