OK, so last time we've played with the unescaped and the boolean attribute in PUG. Let's play some more.
Let's close some of those files, not all of them and in here, into attributes I'll create
style.pug
And I'll also drag style over here, come on.
Close this and close this one and into style
If you have already played with React you might know about
this one otherwise let's do an "a" tag
With a style and in here
Let's pass an object and do: color
With the value of red
And we can see, the style receives this one, over here
Let's also do background
And color, background-colour: blue
However this one should not work and if we open the console we can see that there is an error over there
That's because we need to cameCase
So backgroundColor, like that. If we save it we can see
Color red and background ... actually we don't need to camelCase
Maybe we need to put it in a string. Let's put it in a string
It's not like React, it's not React
Now we've got color: red and background-colour: blue
So that the style one. Now let's create another one
The class attribute.
class.pug
And open the class.pug, close that style
So let's create a couple of arrays over here and I'll do:
class, var class1List = [] and this might sound familiar to you from
Bootstrap, btn and btn-primary
I'll use some examples that you might be already used to
Let's do: var class2List = []
btn-small
And now let's do a div(class=class1List)
If we save it we can see that this array
Has been joined into values using space
So whatever values you'll be inputting in here, maybe like that:
It will be joined. Let's do another one
Another div, a couple of pipes
For whitespace control, and this would be the second one
Ok, so you can see that I also converts it into just a single value over there
However, there is another thing, we can repeat this attribute class
And pass it class1List
Now, if we look into it, it joined, it concatenated
The two arrays into one and then outputted all values with spaces between them
Now lets do some more classes, let's do some more classes. New file
literal-class.pug
Move the pug on top, close that file
No, no. we want this to be
... copy the name of it
And delete that file
And we want to create a new file inside the "attributes" not in the "tmp"
So literal-class.pug and then open
literal-class.html , split it
Horizontally and we are almost there
Ok so literal class means we can do an "a" tag with
.btn as a class and then
Click me
Go away, go away!
So this is like that. You can also do another dot, let's do some pipes
And .btn.btn-small
So we can see that the second one is like that
And we can also do a div, pipe pipe, div
.this-is-a-class
However, if you want to omit the div tag which is in Pug the default one
You can just do the class like in CSS and it will convert
By default into this div, so the default tag in
Literal class in pug is div
You can type the div or you can optionally omit it
So, happy hacking!