Ultima oară ne-am întâlnit cu PUG, acum hai să aflăm cum putem să îmbunătățim procesul
We've created this "peopleList" over here and then we looked through it
and we are generating this HTML over here which is like one liner anyways, it's quite compressed
So in order to generate it we said: pug index.pug -w
and then this would convert index.pug in index.html and each time
we do a change we can see that the change is propagated here, but
It's not easy for us to read, so we can further improve it
-w --pretty
And now it's easier for us to read it
and if we do more changes
Like over here we could say, instead of = we could say
td !! and then we interpolate this one into PUG
Like that and now we can see that
Every place has added two exclamation points and a space
And it's easy to read, however this is not the most efficient setup
And in order to, you know, be better coders
Let's find out another way and to do that I'll open again this
meet-pug and for the moment I'll close this one
Go into meet-pug and just remove it
Let's open again the command line, so press the Start key
Type cmd
D:
cd cool-stuff
cd awesome-stuff
OK, let's google: pug starter
Just google "pug starter" and then you'll find this link
https://github.com/marianzburlea/pug-starter
Click on it. Now, if you haven't
Pressed the star button, just press the Start button over here
Let's, let me show you which one is it. Just to make sure ... this one
There is a Star button. If you see Unstar it means you have already added it to your favourites
If not press that Star button which is located under here
And when you do that, then you can find it under "Your stars"
That's how I favourite all the projects that I'm interested in
And that's how you'll quickly find this one, cause some of them
See, the have like weird names: abs-studio-amf-encoder
You can't really remember this all the time, so
It's easier if you add it to your favourites by pressing the Star button
Anyway, the point is: we go on pug-starter, click the clone button and then click this one
This button, click it to copy it to the clipboard
And then over here we just say:
Git clone and I'll press "Shift + Insert" to paste it and then I'll name it
meet-pug, so
git space clone space paste the URL or type
https://github.com/marianzburlea/pug-starter.git
Space meet-pug
Which will clone the project into a folder named: meet-pug
Now: cd meet-pug
Will type: npm which is node package manager
npm and i for install, OK? So "i" or "install"
is the same thing, just type: npm i
So once this is done, let's open
This folder under Visual Studio Code
So: code .
And into this "src" we can see that we have an index.pug file
With some initial setup
I'll press CTRL + ' to open the command line under Windows
And I'll type: npm start
Now let's add this to the left side
OK, so now over here if we type something and
Save it we can see that it auto-refreshes
And on top of that later on we can also see that later on this project offers
Options to style it, and not just style it, deploy it to GitHub and so on
However we are more interested in PUG so
Let catch up in the next lesson where we'll start to talk about
PUG attributes or attributes in PUG. Happy Hacking!