So how do you write HTML attributes using PUG
Last time if you remember, we created from our simple setup a more advanced one, a more convenient one
So let's get back to it. I'll open the console.
If you haven't closed the process, well, you don't have to do anything, otherwise
You'll have to do: npm start
And basically this will watch for changes
in PUG as well as open a browser
We are not that interested right now in the browser, let's just see how
We can write HTML attributes in PUG
So in this "src" I'll create a new folder
And I'll call it
attributes
And in here I'll create a new file, attributes as well
attributes.pug
Ok, and over here I'll just say: div test
And basically, if I go into "tmp", into attributes
I'll see this attributes.html file, let's split it
And then close that explorer
And we can see that this "div test" gets converted into this one over here
So let's see another example, let's create an "a" tag
In order to do attributes we want to open parentheses
And let's do "href"
=https://google.com
And that's like that. Give me a second, let's split this horizontally
Ok, so ... but those ones are one after the other
Let's try with a pipe here,
What happen? Maybe another one?
Two pipes, yeah. So, with two pipes we can make them
On new lines. Ok, let's see some other ones.
Let's do an "img" tag, so if we just save it
It gets converted into that, and ...
We'll do src=my-pictute.jpg
Save it. We can also use commas or spaces
And we'll do width="100"
Then height, let's do 50
So it's pretty similar to HTML, this img tag gets converted in
Into this one, so it pre-fills the lesser sign
And it also closes it.
And then in the round parentheses that are here, let me quickly do some drawings
So those parentheses and whatever is inside it
Those attributes will be printed in here
So now this is how I do attributes with PUG, let me also show you
Another example. I'll open this one over here and I'll do a new file
multiline-attributes.pug
So if I save it we can see that into "tmp"
multiline-attributes.html has been generated
Now I'll keep the pug on top and the html on the bottom
So let's say you have a meta tag, right? And ...
the name is "description"