So what is a template engine, for HTML or anything else?
Well, let's meet PUG, which is one of the best template engines for HTML out there.
I'll press the "Start" key and R
and it'll open this command, you can just press:
the "Start" key and then type "cmd" and press "Enter"
and it'll open a command line.
so I'll keep those ones close as
I have multiple partitions and I want to change into the D partition
You don't have to do this if you have only one.
I  keep all my stuff in the "cool-stuff" folder
So you've noticed that I've double clicked the "cool-stuff"
In order to change on the D partition
and then go into "cool-stuff" I'll say
change directory "cool stuff"
cd cool-stuff
so we are in the same place, if you look over here:
d:\cool-stuff and d:\cool-stuff
which means: this part over here
is the same as this part over here
those two are one and the same
and now let's continue
in here I'll say: "mkdir" which is make directory
awesome-stuff
so you notice that "awesome-stuff" has been created
I'll change into it:
cd awesome-stuff
which is the same as double clicking  on it
and in here I'll create another one
mkdir meet-pug
and change into it as well
cd meet-pug
so in here I want to start creating some files
I'll quickly open visual studio code by staying
code and space .
and now Visual Studio Code will be opened with the "meet-pug" directory
and over here
I will close this for a second
I'll also close this one
Actually I'll make it just smaller for you to see what happens
And I'll press CTRL + ' on Windows to open the console
Which is the same as this console,
but now we have it in Visual Studio Code so we can close this one
So now, let's see! Do we have PUG?
Well, pug command not found, which means we don't have it.
I'll say: npm install -g which is global
pug-cli
you need to have NodeJS insalled
to be able to run "npm"
to install pug-cli globally to be available for all projects
now let's test if PUG is recognized
something happened or something doesn't happen
which means it's no longer not recognized, it is recognized
so let's see now, I'll create a new file here
named index.pug
and in here I'll type: h1 hello
OK. So if I save it you can see that
there is a new file here and this is the content of it
now let's try: pug index.pug
so now, out of pug, index.pug
PUG converted it into a HTML file and give me a moment
So you can earily see now that
this one, h1,  has been converted into this one over here
so now I'll do something else, instead of always run ....
cause if I type this, it's not reflected in here, so I need to run again: pug index.pug
so in order not to be needed to run always this
I want to say: pug index.pug -w
which is watch, in watch mode
which means now it's watching index.pug
and if I make more changes and save it
you can see that those changes are reflected in here. Now you can easily
close this window over here, the "windows exploer", make this one bigger
and also close this one, cause I know it's watching
so whatever I do here, as soon as I save it it'll be reflected in here
so now about that template engine
In PUG in order to type some JavaScript you can do
minus, and then inside that minus, as
I press a TAB and then I say var, or let or const, whatever
So let's do "var" cause most people are used to this
and I"ll create a list, like people, peopleList
and in order to be a list I'll create an empty array and I'll start populating it with objects
and people have a name so I'll say: name Marian
and age 36
I'll do a comma here and I'll select those lines
I'm going exactly at the beginning of line 3 and using SHIFT and Down Arrow
I select those ones, those lines and then
with ALT + SHIFT pressed I press Down Arrow to duplicate it a few times
and now we've got more of them, that's the first one
Let's do Grace. It's easier for you to understand it in English, Gratiela is my wife
And now Grace is 31, and we've got Razvan. Razvan, how old are you?
25. Twenty five
And we also got Maya, my daughter, which is four
And now you'll get to understand quite quickly
what a template engine is
so if I want to output all those names
into HTML, usually I'd do something like, maybe: table
and then, OK, let's do some HTML
table, /table
let's see, if I save it ... yeah, it's there, OK ...
so then I'll do a "tr" table row
and another tr with close
td, and then another, Marian, slash td
Let's duplicate. This one will be 36.
I want to go through the trouble of actually doing this so you'll see in a second, the benefits of it
so I'll do this as a tbody
and this as a thead, a tbody again, sorry
closing the tbody tag and duplicating this as ... like that
and then this is thead
and Name and age, OK.
so far if I am to ...
actually let's see if there is an "open with explorer", yeah, reveal in explorer ... if I am to open this page
let me drag it here ... you can see there is a table
border equals one
so this is the table and ...
in order to add more name I'll just have to ... do more of this, multiple times, and then
It'll look like this but with the proper names.
this is what I would have to do in HTML
now lets' do it in PUG
So in PUG I would say
table, and than I would say: tbody
see, I'm no longer closing the tags, I'm just using TAB to indent and
then: tr, td Name and td, age
and then at the same level as tbody ... well, this is tbody actually
and this is thead ... over here, I'll do td, again td, Marian and age, 36
so what this does is: it creates this HTML automatically for us
ALT + Z
however, if I have this list over here, peopleList
I can iterate it and I can use either "each" or "for" to do that.
so each people ... people in peopleList
This is the same as using "for". Yeah, I'll comment it but, if you use for or each, it's the same thing.
each peole in peopleList ... and now I'll indent this to be under that each
and I'll say: people is this object, each time it iterates
it's this object, and this object, and this object and so on
and each object has a name and an age
so in here I would say: = people.name
and in here I'd say people.age
So right now, this is the template part, this here, this is the template part
or the view part where we present whatever we want
and this is the model or the data part
and no matter how many other ... let's say: people we have in that list
we always run just one time the repeating part and then PUG generates automatically for us all this.
So if we are to refresh this we'll see
that this code has been generated for us, let's inspect it
actually not inspect, let's do "view source", where is view source?
View page source
Let's also do the inspect one and in inspect we can easily see that
this code has been nicley generated for us
We've got this part over here and then this has been repeated by PUG and generated
without any further intervention, we don't have to do anything
This is PUG guys! I'll see you in the next lesson.